(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-26T20:51:24.812739",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
時は還え 今宵も願う
Time turns back; tonight too, I wish
途切れぬ想い 孤独夜に似た
An unbroken feeling, resembling a lonely night,
定めだと気付かないまま
Unaware that it was destiny,
あなたの姿を探す
I search for your figure.
月よ 月よ 追い掛ける夢
O moon, o moon, the dream I chase—
朽ち果ててしまわないように
So it won't rot away,
ひらり ひらり 舞い踊りましょう
Fluttering softly, let's dance
赤月に消えるまでは 口づけ交わす
Exchanging kisses until we fade into the crimson moon...
あの日の夢は 儚く揺れる
That day's dream sways fleetingly.
永久に続くよに 願っても
Even if I pray for it to last forever,
伝えたい あなたにだけは
I want to convey it, only to you—
物語の結末は 月よ 重ね たどり着く夢
The story's conclusion: O moon, gathering, the dream we reach.
闇に染まってしまわぬよう
So it won't be dyed in darkness,
桜 桜 咲き誇りましょう
Cherry blossoms, cherry blossoms, let's bloom proudly.
いつかあなたが踏み抜く その瞬間まで
Until the exact moment you step through someday—
月よ 月よ 追い掛ける夢
O moon, o moon, the dream I chase,
ふたり続けよう 幾千の時を流れて
Let's continue together, flowing through thousands of years.
時代を超え 今宵も願う
Transcending eras, I still pray tonight,
途絶えぬ想い 届くようにと
so that my unceasing feelings will reach you.
運命だと気付かないまま
Without realizing it's destiny,
貴方の姿を探す
I search for your figure.
一夜一夜 追いかける夢
Night after night, a dream I chase.
はーい、ということで、みんな！
Hi-i, so everyone!
にゃっはろー、にゃっはろー、にゃっはろー！
Nyahallo, nyahallo, nyahallo!
にゃっはろーわー！
Nyahalloworld!
はーい、ということで、ついに！さくらみこ
Hi-i, so, finally! Sakura Miko's
3D新衣装お披露目ライブ、やったー！
3D New Outfit Reveal Live, yay!
視野、やったやったやったやった！
Yay, yay, yay, yay, yay!
みんな見えてますかー？
Can everyone see me?
あ、にゃっはろー！はーい、ということで、
Ah, nyahallo! Hi-i, so,
ホロライブ所属の、エリート巫女、
Hololive's elite shrine maiden,
さくらみこでーす！
Sakura Miko here!
今日はプロレスをしません！笑
Today, I won't be doing pro wrestling! Haha.
はい、もうアイドルに戻ったということで。
Yeah, since I've returned to being an idol.
いや、どうですか、ちょっと
Man, how is it? I tried
ヶ月の夢踊ってみたんですけど。
dancing to "Kagetsu no Yume", but...
いや、今日はね、ちょっとライブのコンセプトとしては、
Yeah, today, for the concept of the live,
あのー普段よりももっとエリートみこっていう感じでね。
um, more than usual, as an even more elite Miko.
ま、今日は、まあこの後分かりますけど、和風の曲が多めになってたりとかします！
You'll see later, there'll be lots of Japanese songs!
やー！
Yay!
ということで、なんだろね、あ、みんなありがとうコメント。あ、見てますよ。あに可愛い！
Thanks for comments! Ah, I see them. You're cute!
みんな、そうでしょう？みこ可愛いじゃん。お久しぶりのみこ服。
Everyone, right? Miko's cute outfit, right?
ね？
Right?
ありがとー！
Thank you!
あの、事前にですね、さくらにこう新衣装予想を募集していたと思うんですけど、
Beforehand, we collected predictions for my new outfit,
やっぱりみこもね、やりとってね、紹介、
and as expected, Miko wanted to introduce them too.
みんなもよくやってますよね？ホロライブのメンバーはね、よくね、やってるので、
Everyone does it, Hololive members often do it too,
ちょっと今日はみこもやってみようと、思います！
so today Miko will try doing it too!
では、じゃあ、早速紹介しますか！
Well then, shall we introduce them right away?
じゃあちょっとね、こっちにあるので持ってきます！
Since it's over here, I'll go get it!
よいしょ、よいっしょっと。いやー、いっぱい届いてたんですけどね、
Heave-ho. Man, a lot of them arrived,
一部、一部だよ！
but just a part of them!
一部しょ、あ、見えてるか、あ、はい！
Part of, ah, can you see? Ah, yes!
では、まず1つ目は、こちら！
Well then, first one is this!
じょじょーん！
Ta-da!
これね、さ、ちょっと、このね、え、天才だろ、これ、ちょっと、
Look at this, wait, isn't this a genius?
天才すぎぬ？こちらのですね、なんか、あの、みこが馬に乗ってるやつ、すごいね、よくシルエットからこんな、作画コスができたな、天才、天才なのか！？
Miko riding a horse? From a silhouette, wow, genius!
はい。いや、この発想はなかったな！
Man, I didn't think of this idea!
いや、今回はね、やはり3Dだから、このね、予想もね、3Dででき、3Dですか？できないこと、みこやりとんねる、にゃっはろー！
Since it's 3D, can predictions be done in 3D? Miko makes it happen!
お、お、お、どう？乗ってるみこの手や、ふふっふふん。
Oh, how is it? Miko's hands riding, hehehe.
おお、とに、似合ってるな。どう？
Oh, it suits me. How's that?
お胸が出ちゃう。
My chest is popping out.
しゅ、なんだこれ？こんなふうになるんですね、3Dのね、お披露目、
So this is how the 3D reveal turns out,
お披露目からのこのね、予想紹介はこんなふうになるんだな、天才だな！
turning prediction intros like this. What a genius!
発想の天才、いや発想の天才ですね、ありがとうございます！
A genius of ideas, thank you very much!
あの、これね、実は、おかあたんも、まりちゃんも好きって言ってました。
Actually, mom and Mari-chan both liked this.
じゃ、こちらですね、はい。
Well then, this one, yes.
では続いてこちら！あ、た、た、た、た、た、た、た、た、た、え、たい！マグマ新衣装。
Now, next is this! Ah, Tai! Magma New Outfit.
まあ、みこはね、よくマグマに突っ込んだりマグマに溶かされたりしますからね。
Miko often dives into magma or gets melted by it.
やばい、これ！これもよく、
This is crazy! This too,
これもよくね、あのシルエットから想像ができたな！
how could you imagine this from that silhouette!
なんかね、ちょっとね
You know, um...
帯に絡み見えてる紐がね、あるんですけど
There's a string visible around the sash, but
これをね、全面に持ってくっていうね
bringing this to the very front,
すごい、いい発想の消火器っていうことですね
that's such a great, imaginative fire extinguisher.
あ、これできないな。
Ah, I can't do this.
これはできないな。
This isn't possible.
はい、こちらの、消火器だ
Yes, this fire extinguisher...
おお、いいね！
Oh, nice!
ちょっとほしいけどね、これ。
I kinda want this, though.
普通にあの、別口でいただけますか？
Can I get this separately, normally?
あ、見て！すごい、8代目って書いてある。
Ah, look! Wow, it says "8th generation."
これエリートらじゃない？
Isn't this Elite-ra?
わあ！新衣装で無理やりエリートらを実感してもらうっていうね
Wow! Making me experience Elite-ra forcibly with a new outfit,
これ神ですね。いいね、ほしいな！
that's god-tier. Nice, I want it!
マイクラで欲しいよ、これ！
I want this in Minecraft!
あ、子供ネタじゃないぞ！
Ah, this isn't child stuff!
すん、わあ！エッチだな。見て、みんな
Whoa! That's lewd. Look, everyone,
あ、ちょっともう、自分の胸を揉んでるかのような
Ah, wait, it looks like I'm massaging my own chest,
やばいやばいやばい！
oh no oh no oh no!
すごい！
Amazing!
可愛い！
Cute!
ちょっと露出度が高めな感じですね
It feels a bit high on the exposure side,
なんかお姉さん。
kind of like an older sister.
いや、これ大丈夫なのか？
Man, is this okay?
これ、ホロライブのラインを超えてないのか？
Does this cross Hololive's line?
超えてないの？このぐらいなら。
It doesn't? If it's about this much.
じゃみこがね、着てみましょう。
Well, let's have Miko try it on.
あ、すごい！ハマり具合がすごい！
Ah, amazing! The fit is amazing!
すごくない？みんな見て。
Isn't it amazing? Everyone look.
あ、でも、外人のところ、う、う、う、う、う、あ
Ah, but, the foreign parts...
あ、どうかな？
Ah, how is it?
みこのへそが見えてんで、でかいお姉さん、お姉さんですよ、みんな。
Miko's belly button is showing, a big older sister, an older sister, everyone.
やはろー、やはろー。
Yaharou, yaharou.
まあまだよ。
Well, not yet.
ういー！
Yay!
いや、いいですね！
Man, this is great!
こちらは素晴らしいね。
This one is wonderful.
可愛い、正統派という感じでね。
Cute, feels quite orthodox.
猫耳もね、可愛い！
And the cat ears, too, cute!
お、やば！
Oh, yikes!
時間がやばい！
Time is running out!
あ、また、うわー！
Ah, again, whoa!
あ、違う！
Ah, no!
はい、パーカー、パーカー！イラストも可愛い。
Yes, hoodie, hoodie! The illustration is also cute.
あ、やはろー！
Ah, yaharou!
みこが出てきてる。
Miko is coming out.
はい、こちらはパーカーの衣装ですね。
Yes, this is the hoodie outfit.
めちゃめちゃ可愛い！
Super cute!
いいね、尻尾が入っとんぜ！イラストも可愛い、猫入ってる。
Nice, it has a tail! The illustration's cute, has a cat.
いいね！これ、キントキのね、モチーフだね、フード。
Nice! This is based on Kintoki, the hood.
これ、自然にさ、頑張ってさ、
Naturally, you know, trying hard,
あの、スタッフの皆さんとね、こうできるようにね、調整してたんだけど、めちゃくちゃシュールだな、うちらは何を頑張っていたんだろう。
with the staff, trying to adjust so we could do this, it's so surreal, what were we even trying hard for?
すごい頑張ったんだよ、この調整。これでも頑張ったんだ。
We worked really hard on this adjustment. We really did.
可愛い、キントキ配膳だね。キントキってのはみその式神だよ。
Cute, Kintoki serving. Kintoki is Miko's shikigami.
みんな、みこぴーの先輩でし。
Everyone, they're Mikopii's seniors.
可愛い、ポンポンも可愛い。
Cute, the pompoms are cute too.
いいね！いいな、みこも。
Nice! Nice, Miko too.
じゃーん！
Ta-da!
あらまー！
Oh my!
これは白無垢、
This is pure white,
お嫁だね、お嫁！お嫁のみこ。
A bride, right, a bride! Miko as a bride.
いいじゃない、これちょっと、またお姉さんだね。
Isn't this nice, this is, again, an older sister vibe.
いつかみかもね、みこぴーもらってくれるんだろ、おまえらは。な？
Someday Miko too, Mikopii will take me, won't you guys? Right?
これがみこのお嫁の衣装だ。
This is Miko's bride outfit.
今はまだ似合わないかもしれないが、
It might not suit me yet right now,
いつか、いつかみこも似合うような素敵なレディになるんだ。
someday, someday I'll become a wonderful lady that it suits.
まだ許してくれないみたいだ。
Looks like they still won't forgive me.
はい、めちゃくちゃ可愛いね！
Yes, super cute!
いいね！
Nice!
これは燃えます、おね、この髪型がめちゃいいな。
This is burning, uh, this hairstyle is so good.
あ、なんでだよ！順番間違えた！
Ah, why! I got the order wrong!
ちょっと最初に持ってくるべきだった！
I should have brought this at the very beginning!
これ、おい、今いい感じだったのに、なんでこんな、ちょっとこんなこと言っちゃいけないけど、古代のロマンセットですね。
Hey, it was going so well, why like this—I shouldn't say this, but it's the ancient romance set.
いやでもこれ一番のハマり具合なんだよな、これ。すごいあれだけど、一番ハマってる気がする。
Man, but this is the best fit of all. It's something else, but I feel like it fits the best.
あなた、同じ顔してるもん！同じ顔してんだよな。
You're making the same face! You're making the exact same face.
ちょっとこわ、これバーチャルこわいよ、バーチャル怖すぎ。
A bit scary, virtual is scary, virtual is way too scary.
がんばれみこ、がんばれ。おにゃはよー！
Do your best, Miko, do your best. Good meowning!
ちょっと待ってよ。なんかすっごい尖ったデザインですね、これは。
Wait a minute. This is a super edgy design, isn't it?
これ、これにどうでしょうか？
How about this one?
これ、これにいけるんじゃないか？
Couldn't we go with this?
そのぐらいの尖ったファッションですね。
That level of edgy fashion.
これかもしれない、ワンチャンな。
This might be it, maybe just maybe.
そんなわけないだろ！
No way that's happening!
続いて…おいしょ。あ、これが幸い！
Next... oof. Ah, fortunately, this one!
あれだな？ちょっとセンシティブ…
Is that it? It's a bit sensitive...
センシティブすぎだよ！大丈夫かこれ？
Too sensitive! Is this okay?
はい。これはね、一番センシティブな、珍獣要素ですね。
Yes. This is, you know, the most sensitive rare beast element.
ちょっと見せていいのかな？
Is it okay to show this?
これね、これもうホロライブサマーだね、ギリギリだね。
This, you know, this is Hololive Summer territory, barely pushing it.
だめですよ、これは！これはだめだ！
No way, this! This is no good!
これわ、だめだ。だめ。
This is no good. No.
これはね、やばい。ちょっと出ている。出ているね。
This is, you know, dangerous. It's sticking out.
なかなかになかなかにセンシティブです。
It's quite, quite sensitive.
そう。これじゃやばいな。過去所。
Yeah. This is bad. Moving on.
あや、やばば。お。あー、やばば。
Whoa, whoa. Oh. Ah, yikes.
はい。いや、でもすごい可愛いデザイン、ありがとうございます。
Yes. Well, but it's a super cute design, thank you very much.
いや、すごいね。みんなすごいな、発想が豊かだ。
Man, that's amazing. Everyone's so amazing, so imaginative.
よし。というわけで、はあ！
Alright. And with that, hah!
いやあ、ちょっと、はあ、たっぷりやってしまったが。
Man, I got a bit too into it.
はい。というわけで、それでは早速ね、お待たせの…
Right. And with that, now without further ado, the long-awaited...
ライブパートが始まります。
live part is starting!
あの、今日ね、ゲストもね、呼んでいるので、誰が来るのかな？楽しみにしていてください。
Um, today, we're calling guests too, so look forward to who comes!
それでは、ゲストパート、レッツゴー！
Well then, guest part, let's go!
パーッとパーッと晴れやかに咲かせましょう 花のように
Brightly and radiantly, let's make it bloom like a flower!
欲しいのは少しの踏み出し方と 弱気な心を開ける魔法のキー
All I want is a little step forward and the magic key to open a timid heart.
勢いよく跳ねて 始まる夢は 本気の夢は 踊れや踊れ
Spring up with momentum, the dream that begins, the serious dream, dance and dance!
もっともっと一緒に数えたい 新しい景色 パーッとパーッと晴れやかに
More and more, I want to count together the new scenery, brightly and radiantly,
咲かせましょう 花のように
let's make it bloom like a flower!
これからの君が見たい
I want to see you from now on.
始まる夢は 本日の君は 踊れや踊れ どんな形？
The dream that begins, you today, dance and dance, in what form?
踊れや踊れ どんな形 踊れや踊れ
Dance and dance, in what form, dance and dance!
散らさないで もっともっと一緒に数えたい 新しい景色
Don't scatter it, more and more together, I want to count the new scenery.
色華にほ パーッとパーッと晴れやかに咲かせましょう 花のように
In blooming colors, brightly and radiantly let's make it bloom like a flower!
これからの君が見たい
I want to see you from now on.
色華にほ パーッとパーッと晴れやかに 咲かせる想いは 絶え間なく
In blooming colors, brightly and radiantly, the feelings we make bloom are ceaseless,
だって求め合うのは 始めかさだと つぶやいてみた 乙女心さ
because what we seek out is the start... I murmured with a maiden's heart.
迷ってるだけなら 何も起こらない
If you're just hesitating, nothing will happen.
強気で行くんだと 瞳で見とるかるよ
Going forward strong, I'll watch it in your eyes.
そしたらさ おいで 明日が見かピカと
Then come on, tomorrow will sparkle brightly,
輝く夢の 本当さ 夢の色に
shining dream's, true dream's color,
変わる 歌いや歌え
changing, sing and sing,
浮かえながら ずっとずっと一緒に遊びたい 桜色ハーモニー
floating along, forever and ever I want to play together in cherry blossom harmony.
ちりぬるを さらさらと流れゆく 歌かたの花の香り
Falling petals flowing smoothly, the scent of ephemeral flowers,
いつまでも君といたい ちりぬるを さらさらと流れゆく
I want to be with you forever, falling petals flowing smoothly,
出逢いと別れに 酔いもせず そっと見つめ合って 君の気配を
without getting drunk on meetings and goodbyes, gently gazing at each other, feeling your presence.
感じていたい
I want to feel it.
乙女の願い
A maiden's wish...
踊れや今こんなに嬉しくて 踊れ ほらこんなに嬉しくて
Dance now, so happy, dance, look, so happy,
気分次第で遠くへ飛ぼうそう 歌えや今こんなに楽しくて 歌え ほらこんなに楽しくて
let's fly far away depending on our mood, sing now, so fun, sing, look, so fun!
パーッとパーッと晴れやかに 咲かせましょう 花のように
Let's make them bloom brilliantly like flowers.
欲しいのは 少しの踏み出しからと
All we need is just a little step forward,
弱気な心を開ける魔法のキー
the magic key to open a timid heart.
それでも「ひっふみい!」 勢いよく跳ねて
Even so, "Here we go!" bounding with high spirits.
始まる夢は(本気の)夢は どんなカタチ?
What shape will our dreams take as they begin?
踊れヤ踊れ 散ラサナイデ
Dance and sing, scatter the petals away!
もっともっと一緒に数えたい 新しい景色
I want to count up even more new sights together with you.
いろはにほ パーッとパーッと 晴れやかに 咲かせましょう 花のように
Irohaniho, let's make them bloom brilliantly like flowers,
桜色ハーモニー
shining bright with a Sakura Harmony!
咲かせたい想いはつねならむ
The feelings we want to make bloom are overflowing—
だって乙女道は風まかせと... つぶやいてみた ...乙女心さ!
or so maidenly pride whispers to itself, orphaning the maiden's heart!
迷っているだけなら何も起こらない
If you're just hesitating, nothing will happen.
強気で行くんだと瞳で語るよ
Speak with your eyes that you'll move forward bravely,
そうしたら「さあ、おいで!」
and then— "Come on, lead the way!"
明日がぴかぴかと輝く夢の(本当さ)夢の色に変わる
Tomorrow turns the color of a dream that shines brightly.
歌エヤ歌エ 浮カネナガラ
Sing and dance, let our spirits float away!
ずっとずっと一緒に遊びたい
I want to keep playing together with you forever.
はい、ということで!
Alright, so...
一番最初のゲストはあやめちゃんとねねちに来てもらいました!
First of all, Ayame-chan and Nenechi came to join us!
やったー!
Yay!
やったー! やったー!
Yay! Yay! Yay!
いや、その組み合わせはちょっと意外ですね。
Man, that combination is a bit unexpected, isn't it?
ねえ!
Right?
お、初めてじゃない?
Wait, is this the first time?
あ、初めて。
Ah, first time!
ねえ、そうかもしれない。
Right? It might be!
ちょっと誘わしていただきましたね。ありがとうございます。
We invited you guys over! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you!
逆にきてもらえてね。
Please come over the other way around sometime too, okay?
どう、みんなかわいいでしょ? 結構、のび、いいよね。
Doesn't it look cute? And also, it's pretty...
ねえ、ちょっと新鮮味が。
Right? It has a sort of fresh vibe to it.
なんか新鮮味がね、あるかなと思って、ね、呼ばしていただいたんですけど。
I thought there might be something fresh about it, so I invited you guys.
イラストかわいすぎるの。
The artwork is too cute!
かわいい!
So cute!
めちゃかわいい! イエーイ!
Super cute! Yay!
というわけで、今日はね、あのミコの新作お披露目ということで、
So today, since it's Miko's new outfit reveal,
はい!
yeah!
ちょっとお二人に、なんとね、新作の予想を描いていただいたんですよ。
The two of you actually drew predictions for the new outfit, didn't you?
描きましたよ!
We did!
やったー! じゃあちょっと持ってきてもらうかな?
Yay! So let's have you bring them out.
はい。
Yes!
よし。よし。
Alright, let's see.
うっ、うっ。よく、よく、あれっ?
Wait, wait!
よ、こっちだ!
Yo, over here!
よ、こっちだ! よいよいよい。
これ、み、み、み、あー、なんとかかんとか。
Wait, let's see— Ah, I can see them!
待って、待って、どっち、どっち、どっち。
Wait, which one is which?
あー、どっちがいいかな?
Wait, which one should we go with?
どっちからいきますか?
Which one should we start with?
どっちにする?
Which one?
じゃあ、待って、ねねちの、待って、ねねちのやつ、あ、待って、待って。
Well, Nenechi's— wait, Nenechi's?
ねねの、ねねのやつなくなった!
Wait, Nenechi's drawing is gone!
ねねの、ねねの、埋まった! ねねの埋まったよ。
Nene's, Nene's— wait, Nene's buried!
あ、じゃあちょっとねねちからいこっかな?
Wait, let's start with Nenechi's then, okay?
オッケー、行こっ。いいの? こうやっていいの?
Okay, let's go. Is this fine? Should I show it?
うーん、多分、きっと変わってるでしょう。
Uhm, it's definitely going to be different, though.
あ、はい、ということでねねちがね、描いてくれました、この新衣装のやつ。
Ah! Okay, so Nenechi drew this.
こんな感じにしましたー。
This is what it looks like!
なんか、和風の...
It's kind of like a Japanese-style...
和風の猫耳メイドみたいな感じかな?
Cat-ear maid, or something like that?
あ、いいですね。え、この髪型は?
Oh, that's nice. Wait, what about this hairstyle?
髪型...髪型？
Hairstyles?
なんか、クレオパトラみたいな感じ？
It's like Cleopatra or something.
まあ、そうかね、あの猫耳がついているからね。
Well, it's because she has cat ears, right?
そうそう、で、これ絶対頭に耳がついているだろうなと思って。
Right, right, and this surely has ears under the hair, right? I thought.
面白い、その予想は完璧なんだけど、でも、あ、当ってるところもありけり。
It's funny how you got the prediction totally right, but also got things totally wrong in places.
あれ、本当?当たってる?
Wait, really? You're guessing?
みこ、全然、それ見てないでしょ?
Miko, you're looking at it and seeing it for the first time?
これ、あれじゃない?できるんじゃない?これ。
Well, this isn't what it actually looks like, right?
うそ。顔だけ。顔だけみたいにできる?
Only the face—can we make just the face?
う、う、う、あ、お、お、あ。
Wait! Ah, okay!
待って、待って、待って、待って、その、待ってこと。え、かわいい!これメイド服みたいな感じ?
Wait, wait, wait, what? So cute! It's like a maid outfit!
あ、そうそうそう、なんか和風のメイドさん
Ah, yes, yes, yes. Like a traditional maid-san...
みたいな感じで、露出もあり。
kind of vibe, with some skin showing too.
いや、いいですね。
Yeah, it's nice, isn't it?
いいですね。
It is nice!
あ、でもね、シルエットが結構分かりづらいからね、これは難しいかった。
Well, the silhouette is kind of hard to tell, though, isn't it? This is...
難しかった。
It was hard.
あ、直りました!やった!
Alright, it's fixed! Yay!
直りましたよ!
It's fixed, yo!
じゃあ、はい。じゃあ、よがね、こんなキリ
Alright, then Ayame's...
予想、あっ、ちょっと、よが抜けちゃう。お!
Wait, I lost my place.
かっこいい!
It's pretty cool!
ちょっとねねちと違うね。
It's a bit different from Nenechi's, right?
そうだな、ちょっとリボンの感じはちょっと似てるとおもう。
That's right, but the ribbon part probably looks a bit similar, I think.
似ている。たしかに、たしかに。
It does, it does.
なんかちょっと、ぽんちょ、ポンチョっぽいかな?って思ってね、ちょっと羽織っているんじゃないかっていう。
And it looks kind of like a... poncho?
ぽんちょ！
A poncho!
かわいい。
How cute.
個人的な好みで、腕にリボンをつけておりますけど。
I personally love this style, so I added ribbons on the sleeves too, but...
かわいい!
Cute!
感じにしてみました。
I made it into that kind of style.
でもどっちも、あ、はずれてる。
Well, both are... wait, it's coming off!
頭、頭出てる。
The head—the head is coming off!
お、似合う。
Oh, it fits!
え、似合うよ!似合うよ!
Ah, it suits her! It suits her!
おいしい、かわいい。
It suits her, it's cute.
なんか付いて出ててもいいな、ちょっと。
It looks like it's sticking out a bit—wait.
ありがとうございます、描いていただいてね。
Thank you very much for drawing these!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you!
ていうことで、まあ、これはね、お二人もこの後の御披露目をお楽しみにということでね。
So, these two can look forward to seeing the real thing later too!
お楽しみ!どんな人なんだろう?
We're looking forward to it! What kind of person will it be?
まだね、見えてないからね、お楽しみですね。
Well, since we haven't seen it yet, it's something to look forward to!
はい！ ということでね、
Right! So,
ねねちとあやみとにきてもらえました。
we had Nenechi and Ayamito come join us.
ありがとー！
Thank you!
ありがとう！ ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
じゃあ次の曲いきます。
Now, let's move on to the next song.
ありがとね！ がんばってね！
Thanks! Do your best!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
それでは次の曲いこうぞ！
Now then, let's go to the next song!
色付く想いは 切ない百花繚乱花吹雪
Feelings that take color are a bittersweet, riotous storm of cherry blossoms.
ぱっと咲いて散った 花は終わりを告げてく
Flowers that bloom in a flash and fall announce their end;
その時は まだのくせに ことは進まず
Though that time is not yet here, things do not progress.
ちょっと触れて知った 胸の内の温かさを 初めてのこの気持ちだけ 独り占めしていた
The warmth in my chest I learned by touching just a little— I was keeping this brand-new feeling all to myself.
あっさり変わった 夜行快速は 本物だって きっと信じてる
The night express that easily changed— I'm sure it's the real deal.
色褪せぬ微笑みと 花に見せられた少女たち
Girls enchanted by flowers, with smiles that never fade.
あぁ 花に 花に 花に 落ちる花と舞い踊れ
Ah, dance with the falling cherry blossoms, flower by flower!
若さ故の過ちでも 重いことの間に込めてみた 誰も皆 焦がれる 現世の理よ
Even if it's a mistake of youth, I tried putting heavy feelings in between. Everyone yearns for it—the logic of this mortal world.
色付く想いは 切ない百花繚乱花吹雪
Feelings that take color are a bittersweet, riotous storm of cherry blossoms.
ふっと吹き消した 夜を灯す月明かりに
The moonlight illuminating the night that was blown out
あいまいな 心が揺れて 声は響き出す
makes my uncertain heart sway, and my voice begins to echo.
もっと触れたくて 夢をなぞる指先さえ いつも日が 果せた形を 忘れかけていた
Wanting to touch more, even my fingertips tracing dreams were beginning to forget the shape the sun once left.
浮世の波にたゆたう時 厄介な夢は はじけてく
When wavering in the waves of this floating world, troublesome dreams burst apart.
遠い奥山に 荒れる思い立ちは 順序を そのなびき繰り
Feelings raging in the distant deep mountains, putting things in order,
心揺るねき 歌うはツゲッカ
my heart swaying as I sing, Tsugekka.
朝日よ 見にしと 思い踏み込むこの世界は 誰も皆 焦がれる 現世の理よ
As the morning sun pierces through, stepping into this world with those thoughts— everyone yearns for it, the logic of this mortal world.
色付く想いは 切ない百花繚乱花吹雪
Feelings that take color are a bittersweet, riotous storm of cherry blossoms.
風に舞う 音の順序 咲き誇れ
Dancing in the wind, the order of sounds, bloom in full glory!
あっさり変わった 夜行快速は
The night express that easily changed—
本物だって きっと信じてる
I'm sure it's the real deal.
色褪せぬ微笑みと 花に見せられた少女たち
Girls enchanted by flowers, with smiles that never fade.
あぁ 花に 花に 花に 落ちる花と舞い踊れ
Ah, dance with the falling cherry blossoms, flower by flower!
若さ故の過ちでも 重いことの間に込めてみた
Even if it's a mistake of youth, I tried putting heavy feelings in between.
誰も皆 焦がれる 現世の理よ
Everyone yearns for it—the logic of this mortal world.
色付く想いは 切ない百花繚乱花吹雪 風に舞う 音の順序 咲き誇れ
Feelings that take color are a bittersweet, riotous storm of cherry blossoms. Dancing in the wind, the order of sounds, bloom in full glory!
はーい！ ということでね！
Hooray! And so...
あれ？なんか一人違うな？
Huh? Is someone different?
あれ？なんか、おれ、違う？ え、なんで？違う？違わないよ！
Huh? Wait, am I different? Eh, why? Different? No, it's not different!
あ、どうもみなさん、いろはにほへとみこふまみです！
Ah, hello everyone, we are Irohanihoheto Miko Fumami!
あれ？ あれなんか違うな？ なんか違うくないか？
Huh? Huh, something's different? Doesn't it feel a bit different?
俺だよ、俺！お前ちょっと待て、お前、どうやってやったんだよ！ お前ちょっと待て！
It's me, me! Wait a second, how did you do that?! Wait a second!
ちょっとね、あの、やっぱり憧れもありましてね。
Well, you know, after all, I had this yearning for it.
みこもほら、神社だしさ。 あ、確かにそれは。
Miko's shrine maiden too, you see. Ah, true, that's right.
鬼ではないけどさ、血の気が多いかなと思って ちょっと、あの、参加させていただきましたね。
Though I'm not an oni, I thought I've got quite a fiery spirit, so I asked to join in.
そうだね。 さっきまであやみともいたんだよ。 ちょうどね。
That's true. Until just now, Ayamito was here too. Just right.
お嫁ちゃんいってね！
Go find a bride, okay?
お嫁ちゃんどこに当たるんだろえ！？
Whose bride will she end up being?!
っていうことで今日
So today,
あの新書のお披露目ということでね
as part of the new outfit reveal...
あの巫女この後新書お披露目するんですけど
Miko is going to reveal her new outfit soon,
いや楽しみだなー楽しみだー
and I'm so excited!
どうなるのかなー？ねーどうなるんだろうね
I wonder what it'll look like?
まああのまお楽しみなんですけどさっきもね
Well, it's a surprise, but earlier...
まああやみちゃんとあとねねちに、衣装の予想を書いてもらっててんですよ。
we had Ayame-chan and Ne-ne-chi draw their predictions for the outfit.
でね、まあお二人にも書いていただきましたよね。
And you two wrote them down for us, right?
そうです。書かせていただきましたー。やったー。
That's right. We wrote them. Yay!
ということでじゃあちょっと持ってきてもらうのかな。
So, shall we have you bring them out?
持ってきましょうかね。
Let's go get them.
お楽しみだなー。
I'm so excited.
よいしょよいしょ。
Heave-ho.
4台よ。
Four units!
4台じゃないだろ！なんだ君に。
Not four units! What are you talking about?
違うぞ！なんも考えとらんかったんか？
That's wrong! Didn't you think about this at all?
なんも考えてなかった。
I didn't think at all.
ということで、はい！あー来た！
So, here they are! Oh, they're here!
いいですかじゃあ？
Ready, then?
はいはいはいはい。おー、いいですね。
Alright. Oh, nice.
あれなんか、露出がすごくないな。
Wait, aren't they super revealing?
やっぱ露出が多い方がいいかなと。
Well, I thought more exposure would be better.
なるほどなるほど、てるてる坊主？てるてる坊様なのかな、あった！
I see, I see. A teru-teru bozu? Is it a teru-teru bozu?
あでも、え、すごいね、二人とも同じ考えなんだね。
Oh, wait, you two had the exact same idea.
ちょっと露出の違いはあるけど
Though there's a difference in exposure.
本当だ、ずっと似てる。
True, they're quite similar.
雨降ってるね。なんかかぶってんのかなと思って。
It's raining. So I thought maybe we matched.
で、下になんか水着だけど、下はちょっと水着センシティブだから、なんか
And underneath is swimwear, but swimwear is a bit sensitive, so...
くびれね、なみこ、くびれだよ。
The waist, Nami-ko, the waist!
みこだよ、ビートバンもね、出てきてますけど
It's Miko! There's also a kickboard here.
なんかこのみこち、なんかちょっとペーがナーフされている気がする。なんか戦いそうだな、なんか。
It feels like Miko's chest got nerfed a bit here. Looks like she's ready for battle.
それじゃないね、腕にビートバンつけてね。
Not that, she has kickboards attached to her arms.
そういうことね、泳げてから、まあ
Ah, so she can swim, well...
ありがとう、機能ではあるけど
Thanks, it has functionality though.
なるほどね、じゃあ着てもろてじゃあ。
I see. Then let's try wearing it.
じゃあ着てみますかね。うん。
Shall we try wearing it? Yeah.
のののの。
No-no-no-no.
どう？あ、いいね、いいね、いいね。
How is it? Oh, nice, nice, nice!
いいじゃん、いいじゃん。
Looks good!
なるほどね。ホロライブサマーかも。
I see. Could be Hololive Summer.
ありえないね、うんうん。
Unlikely, yeah.
もしかしてこれでホロライブサマーある？
Could Hololive Summer actually be this?
さすがにちょっとあれなんだね、ビートバン腕につけてるホロライブサマーはちょっと
Wearing kickboards on her arms for Hololive Summer is a bit...
だめかな？だめじゃないけどさ
Is that bad? Not bad, but...
なんか、よくないか。やっぱ露出はね、ちょっとね、したい気持ちもあるから、まあ、まあ、そうなんですかね。
Well, maybe not. After all, I do feel like showing some skin, so... Is that how it is?
あ、兄者、あにじゃあ、あれなんですね、いいんですね。
Oh, Ani-ja, I see, that's fine.
後ろから入ってるチョロ、なんか、三尊目のクダかなみたいな。
The straw coming from behind... is it like a third-generation pipe?
違うときこれ、サマのクダだったのかな？ほら。
Wait, could this be a summer pipe? Look.
ああ、ありがとうございます。はいはいはいはい。
Ah, thank you very much. Right, right.
で、みおのは？
And Mio's?
うん、うちはね、これ、雨でも平気だにえ！
Yeah, mine is this: "Rain is no problem at all!"
あ、でも可愛い。なんかミコピン好きそうだな、これ。
Ah, but it's cute. Mikopin would probably like this.
可愛い。これはね、あのね幼稚園児がよく着てる黄色のカッパを着せました。
Cute. For this, I put on a yellow raincoat like kindergarteners often wear.
あーかわいい！
Ah, cute!
あ、ちゃんと長靴も履いててさ。
Oh, she's wearing rain boots too.
多分猫のしっぽなのかなと思ってつけました。
I added them thinking it might be a cat's tail.
長靴も履いてて
And wearing rain boots...
あ、これあれだね、
Ah, this is like...
信号渡る時の黄色い旗も欲しいね。
You'd want a yellow flag for crossing the street.
あ、かわいい！
Ah, cute!
雨でも平気だね！
Rain is no problem!
みこんち、かわいいね。
Miko-chi is so cute.
あ、これかわいいね、これかもしれない正解。
Oh, this is cute. This might be the correct answer!
もしかしたら、梅雨に突入するしね。
Maybe, since the rainy season is starting.
そうそう、そういえばこの季節はそういうことなの？
That's right, speaking of which, is that what this season is about?
いやあ、さすがにね、季節読んじゃいましたよね。
Well, as expected, we read the season right.
ああ、そういうことか。
Ah, I see.
もう、確かにね、まあ、これもあってるかもしれないね。
Yeah, true, this might be right too.
正解に限りなく近いかも
It might be extremely close to the correct answer.
うん、でもめっちゃかわいい。
Yeah, but it's super cute.
ね、でもホロライブサマーも
But Hololive Summer too...
諦めたくないですね。サマーも諦めたくない、そうですね。
I don't want to give up on summer either. Yeah, exactly.
ホロライブ梅雨もあるかも。
Maybe there's Hololive Rainy Season.
梅雨、梅雨、梅雨って！
Rainy season, rainy season!
すごいしね、ありがとうございます、わざわざ書いていただいていいえいいえ。
It's amazing, thank you so much for drawing this. Not at all.
で、この後ね、お楽しみのお披露目があるので、ぜひ見ていてください。
And now, since we have the exciting reveal coming up, please be sure to watch.
楽しみにしていてね。正解かな、これがね。
Look forward to it. Is this the right one?
いや、今後もね、ちょっと新メンバーとして
Well, also as a new member...
ほら、いろはにほへとやフブミの中にみこも入れてもらって、
Having Miko included in Iroha ni Hoheto and Fubuki...
みこも入れてよ！入れてよ！
Include Miko too! Include me!
それじゃ、お披露目だー！
And now, the reveal!
斗あまだれふたつ今日越えて
Exceeding two raindrops today,
果ては夢か幻か
is the end a dream or an illusion?
さあさ今宵お聞かせたまうのは
Now, now, what I will let you hear tonight is
修羅と散る物語
a story of fading into the Asura.
浅き夢見し
Dreaming a shallow dream...
あさき夢見し 歌たねの中で
I dreamed a shallow dream while dozing,
一度の定めは 各も儚きもの
Fate is so fleeting, each and every time.
己が刀 七つ花
Seven flowers upon my blade,
相容れぬは恥ずかしむじ この世は謳かた
What cannot be reconciled is shameful; this world is fleeting.
流るるままに
As it flows along.
十二あまり二つ酔いもせず
Twelve, over two, without even getting drunk—
見るは夢か幻か
Is what we see a dream or an illusion?
さあさ誰も彼もが手を叩く あな懐し仇桜
Now, everyone claps their hands. Ah, nostalgic cherry blossoms of vengeance,
夜明けに散るとも知らず
Not knowing they will scatter at dawn.
勝つも負けるも時の運ならば
Whether you win or lose, if it's up to fate,
覚悟を決めていざ推して参れ
Make your resolve and march right in!
人は流れ て何処へ行く
People drift away, where do they go?
涙 流れて何処へ行く
Tears flow away, where do they go?
君よ哀しと思うても
Even if I think of you with sorrow,
今日を限りと決めた命よ
O life, whose end was decided today.
知るが花恋心 叶わぬならいっそこの世は謳かた
Knowing is the flower of love; if it cannot be, then this world is truly fleeting,
流るるままに
As it flows along.
十二今日を超えて 見るは鬼か人の子か
Twelve, beyond today—is what I see a demon or a child of man?
さあさ得手も不得手も手を叩け
Now, clap your hands, whether skilled or not.
あら楽しや花の宴 湖面の日さへ捕らう
Ah, what joy, a banquet of flowers, catching even the moon on the lake's surface.
あさき夢見し 歌たねの中で
I dreamed a shallow dream while dozing,
一度の定めは 各も儚きもの
Fate is so fleeting, each and every time.
知るが花恋心 叶わぬならいっそこの世は謳かた
Knowing is the flower of love; if it cannot be, then this world is truly fleeting,
流るるままに
As it flows along.
十二今日を超えて 見るは鬼か人の子か
Twelve, beyond today—is what I see a demon or a child of man?
さあさ得手も不得手も手を叩け
Now, clap your hands, whether skilled or not.
あら楽しや花の宴 湖面の日さへ捕らう
Ah, what joy, a banquet of flowers, catching even the moon on the lake's surface.
あさき夢見し 歌たねの中で
I dreamed a shallow dream while dozing,
一度の定めは 各も儚きもの
Fate is so fleeting, each and every time.
己が刀 七つ花
Seven flowers upon my blade,
相容れぬは恥ずかしむじ のう……
What cannot be reconciled is shameful...
回レ!雪月花
Spin! Setsugetsuka
せ~の いちにさんはい!
Ready, one, two, three, go!
ほい! いよ~っ ぽん!
Hoi! Iyo-pon!
さあささ これよりご覧いただきますのは カブキ者たちの栄枯盛衰
Now then, what you are about to witness is the rise and fall of the kabuki outlaws.
時代は常に日進月歩
The times are always making daily progress.
聞いてってよ老若男女
Listen up, young and old, men and women!
一見は勧善懲悪 悪者どもを一刀両断
At a glance, it's virtue rewarded and vice punished, cutting villains down in one stroke.
「でも本当にそれだけで楽しいの?」
"But is it really fun with just that?"
もうなんだってこんにゃく問答
Endless konnyaku questions and answers.
どこからともなく現れて すぐどこかへ行っちゃって神出鬼没
Appearing out of nowhere and vanishing just as quickly, elusive as ghosts.
チャンスを待ったら一日千秋
Waiting for a chance feels like a thousand autumns in a single day.
追いかければ東奔西走
Chasing them takes you running to the four winds.
時代は常に千変万化
The times are constantly changing in myriad ways.
人の心は複雑怪奇
The human heart is complex and bizarre.
「でも本気でそんなこと言ってんの?」
"But are you seriously saying that?"
もうどうにも満身創痍
Covered in wounds and battered all over.
ああ巡り巡って夜の街 キミは合図出し踊り出す
Ah, wandering through the night town, you give the signal and start to dance!
はぁ~ 回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ!
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Like scattering petals gorgeously,
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ! 髪も振り乱して
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin! Disheveling your hair as well,
一昨日、昨日、今日と、明日と、明後日と、この宴は続く
The day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, and the day after, this banquet continues.
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ!
Dance, sing, spin with all your heart!
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is snow, moon, and flowers.
せーの、いちにっさんはいっ！
Ready, one, two, three, go!
ほい！
Hoi!
いよーーーっ ぽん！
Yo---h, pon!
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハイや
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha hai-ya!
ハッハッハッハッハッハッハッハ う〜
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha u~
さあさあさあ
Now, now, now,
これよりご覧いただきますのは
what you are about to see
カブキ者たちの栄枯盛衰
is the rise and fall of the kabukiers.
時代は常に日進月歩
Times are constantly making daily progress;
聞いてってよ老若男女
listen up, men and women of all ages!
一見は勧善懲悪
At first glance, it's reward good and punish evil,
悪者どもを一刀両断
cleaving villains in a single stroke.
「でもホントにそれだけで楽しいの？」
"But is it really that fun alone?"
もうなんだって紆余曲折
Whatever the case, it's full of twists and turns.
ほい！いよーーーっ ぽん！
Hoi! Yo---h, pon!
どこからともなく現れて
Appearing from out of nowhere,
すぐにどこか行っちゃって神出鬼没
and vanishing just as quickly like a phantom.
チャンスを待ったら一日千秋
Waiting for a chance feels like a thousand autumns,
追いかければ東奔西走
chasing after it from east to west.
時代は常に千変万化
Times are always changing in a thousand ways,
人の心は複雑怪奇
and human hearts are intricately bizarre.
「でも本気でそんなこと言ってんの？」
"But are you really serious about that?"
もうどうにも満身創痍
Anyway, I'm covered in bruises.
ああ、巡り巡って夜の街
Ah, wandering round and round the night town,
キミは合図出し踊り出す
you give the signal and start to dance.
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ!
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Like scattering gorgeous petals,
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ!
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
髪も振り乱して
Letting your hair fly wild,
一昨日、昨日、今日と、明日と、明後日と
the day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, and the day after—
この宴は続く
this banquet continues.
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ!
Dance, sing, and spin with single-minded devotion!
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is snow, moon, and flowers.
ねぇねぇねぇ
Hey, hey, hey,
この世に平安訪れるの？
will peace ever visit this world?
のべつ幕無し丁丁発止
Unceasing battles and fierce clashes,
兵ども千客万来
warriors arriving in endless streams,
ひしめき合う群雄割拠
rival warlords jostling for power.
伸ぶるか反るか一攫千金
Rise or fall, a chance at a fortune,
気付いたら絶体絶命
before you know it, you're in mortal peril.
「でも本音のとこ、どうなってんの？」
"But honestly, what's really going on?"
もうまったく奇想天外
Completely out of this world!
ああ、辿り辿って夜の街
Ah, tracing our steps through the night town,
迷いひとつなく踊り出す
we start to dance without a single doubt.
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ!
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Like scattering gorgeous petals,
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ!
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
髪も振り乱して
Letting your hair fly wild,
一昨日、昨日、今日と、明日と、明後日と
the day before yesterday, yesterday, today, tomorrow, and the day after—
この宴は続く
this banquet continues.
踊レ、歌エ、一心不乱に回レ!
Dance, sing, and spin with single-minded devotion!
今宵は雪月花
Tonight is snow, moon, and flowers.
花で一つ、鳥で二つ
One for the flowers, two for the birds,
手打ち鳴らす
clapping our hands in rhythm.
風で三つ、ああ、月出て四つ
Three for the wind, ah, four as the moon rises,
鳴らす鳴らす……
making it echo, making it echo...
花で一つ、鳥で二つ
One for the flowers, two for the birds,
手打ち鳴らす
clapping our hands in rhythm.
風で三つ、ああ、月出て四つ
Three for the wind, ah, four as the moon rises,
鳴らす鳴らす……
making it echo, making it echo...
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ回レ!
Spin, spin, spin, spin, spin, spin!
華麗に花弁 散らすように
Like scattering gorgeous petals...
はーい、ということで、みなさーん！
Hi there, everyone!
はーい、ということで、え、新衣装をお披露目しちゃいました！変身したよ！
So, uh, I've revealed my brand new outfit! I transformed!
どうですか？
How is it?
かわいい？
Cute?
どう？どう？見てみて、ショートパンツなの。
How do you like it? Look, look, they're short pants.
見て、みんな、念願の、念願の紐が帰ってきたよ！
Look everyone, the long-awaited strings are back!
パンツ見えなければいいだよってことで、帰ってきたよ、やったー！
As long as my panties don't show, it's fine, so they're back, yay!
どう、かわいい？みんな。
How is it, are they cute, everyone?
ちょっとね、今回は、あの、前ではあるんですけど、結構いろんなパターンが出てちょっとシルエットとね、違うでしょ？
Well this time, from the front, it has quite a few patterns so the silhouette is a bit different, right?
予想できなかったでしょ？んな！
You couldn't have guessed it, right? Nna!
でね、ちょっとね、かっこいい、ちょっとかっこいいところもありつつ、みこっぽい感じで仕立てていただきました。
And you know, while having some cool parts, it was tailored in a Miko-like vibe.
応援してていて、ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you so much for supporting me! Thank you!
近く、YouTube組が、あの、なんかプツプツだけど、大丈夫かな？
Lately, the YouTube stream is crackling a bit, I wonder if it's okay?
大丈夫？ねえ、見えてるみんな？ありがとう！
Are you okay? Hey, can everyone see me? Thank you!
で、見て、尻尾、分かる？尻尾、尻尾もあるんだ！すごいんでしょ、尻尾も生えたよ！
And look, can you see the tail? There's a tail too!
イエイ！
Yay!
そしてね、ちょっと最初はあの、髪長かったけど、見て、切ってみた！パーチェルだからね、切ったり入れたりできるんだ！
And also, at first my hair was long, but look, I cut it!
どう？かわいい？
How is it? Cute?
あの、意外と前面の方は露出がなくて、あの、ね！
Surprisingly, the front doesn't have much exposure, you know!
だからちょっと、まあ露出も多めにしてみたよ！
So I tried making the exposure a bit more generous!
どなたか、意外と、ちょっと、戦いそうじゃね？
Surprisingly, doesn't it look like I'm ready for battle?
あとね、見て、おへそ、ちょっとボタンを付け忘れていまいますが、どうかなどこかな、恥ずかしいね！
Also look, my navel... I forgot to put a button on it, I wonder how it looks, how embarrassing!
ここだけ見るとやばい！やばすぎる！なんかやばいな。
Just looking here is dangerous! Too dangerous!
どうせ後ろもね、ちゃんとね、クロス、背中も見れるようにしてももらいました！
And the back too, properly crossed, so you can see my back as well!
やっぱ背中はきれいでないとね。
Got to keep your back looking pretty, you know.
あ、ほら見て。
Ah, look here.
横も、いいね！
The side too, looks great!
わぁーい！わぁ、横も見てもらえて嬉しい。やった！
Yay! I'm so happy you can see the side too. Yay!
はい、ということで、まぁね、まだまだありますから、
So, well, there's still more to come,
みんな、最後まで見ていってね。がんばったから。よろしくな！
everyone, keep watching till the end. I worked hard. Please look forward to it!
よろしく。みんな。応援して、みんな。応援よろしく。
Please. Everyone. Cheer for me, everyone. Thanks for your support.
がんばるって言ってね。がんばるよ！
Tell me you'll do your best. I'll do my best!
はい、それでは、じゃあ次の曲、行きますか！がんばるぞ！
Alright then, shall we go to the next song! I'll do my best!
それでは、次の曲いくぞー！
Now then, let's go to the next song!
江戸の町は今日も深く
The streets of Edo are deep today,
夜の帳かけていく
wrapped in the veil of night.
鏡向いて紅を引いて
Facing the mirror, putting on rouge,
応じるまま受け入れるまま
accepting whatever comes, as it is.
橙輝やいた花
Orange-shining flowers
憧れてた望んでいた
that were longed for and desired.
いつのまにか藍色の花
Before I knew it, blue flowers,
けれども私安くないわ
but I'm not that cheap.
誠はただ一人の誰かのためだけに咲きたかったのだけれど
Though I truly wanted to bloom for just one person,
運命は町の自由を奪い、そうして歯車を廻していくのだアンス
fate stole my freedom and turns the gears, that's how it is.
偽りだらけの恋愛
A love full of falsehoods,
そして私を抱くのね
and you embrace me.
悲しくくらいに感じたふりの吉原今日は雨
Pretending to feel it to a sad degree, Yoshiwara is rainy today.
あなた様どうか私を、買っていただけないでしょうか
My lord, won't you please buy me?
さあきだ、傘の群れに
Blooming now, in a crowd of umbrellas,
濡れる私は、雨
I am the rain getting wet.
ああ、あなた様どうか私と
Ah, my lord, won't you please
一夜限りの戯れを
have a night of play with me?
行き交う群れには声がひしめき合いもつれ合い
The passing crowd's voices jostle and tangle,
願うことはどうかいつか鳥籠の外連れ出して
wishing someday to be taken away from this birdcage.
誠はどうかなどなくなってしまったのだけれど
Though truth has somehow completely vanished,
籠の中の過去の中から見える景色だけは、わっちをいつでも時も癒やしてくれるのだアンス
the scenery seen from within this cage always heals me.
偽りだらけの恋愛
A love full of falsehoods,
そして私を抱くのね
and you embrace me.
悲しくくらいに感じたふりの吉原今日は雨
Pretending to feel it to a sad degree, Yoshiwara is rainy today.
私に咲いた花びら、濡れる心に降るは雨
Petals blooming on me, the rain falling on my soaking heart.
あなた様どうか私と、一夜限りの戯れを
My lord, won't you please have a night of play with me?
望む染みの数が、心に刺さる
The number of desired stains pierce my heart,
憂いを帯びた花、望む果てる
a flower tinged with sorrow, longing to end.
どんな、もう見た花、望む果てる
Whatever flowers I've already seen, longing to end...
飼い主だから夜の匂いに吐息ああと聞かせて
As a pet, let out a sigh into the night's scent.
悲しくくらいに感じたふりの吉原今日は雨
Pretending to feel it to a sad degree, Yoshiwara is rainy today.
偽りだらけの恋愛、そして私を抱くのね
A love full of falsehoods, and you embrace me.
悲しくくらいに感じたふりの吉原今日は雨
Pretending to feel it to a sad degree, Yoshiwara is rainy today.
私に咲いた花びら、濡れる心に降るは雨
Petals blooming on me, the rain falling on my soaking heart.
あなた様どうか私と、一夜限りの戯れを望む
My lord, won't you please desire a night of play with me?
染みの数が、二服心に刺さる
The number of stains pierce my heart deeply.
どんな、もう見た花、望む果てる
Whatever flowers I've already seen, longing to end...
千本桜夜に紛れ
Thousands of cherry blossoms blending in the night,
君の声も届かないよ
even your voice cannot reach.
此処は宴鋼の檻
This place is a banquet's steel cage,
その断頭台で見下ろして
look down from that guillotine.
三千世界常世之闇
In the eternal darkness of three worlds,
大胆不敵にハイカラ革命
With a bold and sudden high-collar revolution
磊々落々反戦国家
Uninhibited and carefree, an anti-war state
日の丸印の二輪車転がし
Riding on a Hinomaru motorcycle,
悪霊退散 ICBM
Warding off evil spirits like an ICBM
環状線を走り抜けて 東奔西走なんのその
Running through the loop line, going east and west with ease
少年少女戦国無双 浮世の随に
Boys and girls in the Sengoku era, at the floating world's whim
千本桜 夜に紛れ 君の声も届カナイヨ
A thousand cherry blossoms lost in night, your voice can't reach me
此処は宴 鋼の檻 その断頭台で見下ろして
This is a banquet in a steel cage, looking down from the guillotine
三千世界 常世之闇 嘆ク唄モ聞コレナイヨ
Three thousand worlds, eternal darkness, your lament cannot be heard
青藍の空 遥か彼方 その光線銃で打ち抜いて
Far beyond the indigo sky, shooting through with that ray gun
百戦錬磨の見た目は将校
Looking like seasoned officers,
いったりきたりの花魁道中
Going back and forth on the courtesans' procession
アイツもコイツも皆で集まれ
Everyone, come gather around,
聖者の行進 わんっ つー さん しっ
The march of saints, one, two, three, four!
賽銭門を潜り抜け 安楽浄土厄払い
Slipping past the coin gates, cleansing evil in paradise
きっと終幕は大団円 拍手の合間に
Surely the finale is a grand ending, amidst the applause
千本桜 夜に紛れ 君の声も届カナイヨ
A thousand cherry blossoms lost in night, your voice can't reach me
此処は宴 鋼の檻 その断頭台で見下ろして
This is a banquet in a steel cage, looking down from the guillotine
三千世界 常世之闇 嘆ク唄モ聞コレナイヨ
Three thousand worlds, eternal darkness, your lament cannot be heard
希望の丘 遥か彼方 その閃光弾を打ち上げろ
Far beyond the hill of hope, launching that flashing flare up
千本桜 夜に紛れ 君が歌い僕は踊る
A thousand cherry blossoms lost in night, you sing and I dance
此処は宴 鋼の檻 その断頭台を飛び降りて
This is a banquet in a steel cage, leaping down from the guillotine
千本桜 夜に紛れ 君が歌い僕は踊る
A thousand cherry blossoms lost in night, you sing and I dance
此処は宴 鋼の檻 さあ光線銃を撃ちまくれ
This is a banquet in a steel cage, now fire away with that ray gun!
賽銭門を潜り抜け 安楽浄土厄払い
Slipping past the coin gates, cleansing evil in paradise
きっと終幕は大団円 拍手の合間に
Surely the finale is a grand ending, amidst the applause
千本桜 夜に紛れ 君の声も届カナイヨ
A thousand cherry blossoms lost in night, your voice can't reach me
此処は宴 鋼の檻 その断頭台で見下ろして
This is a banquet in a steel cage, looking down from the guillotine
三千世界 常世之闇 嘆ク唄モ聞コレナイヨ
Three thousand worlds, eternal darkness, your lament cannot be heard
希望の丘 遥か彼方 その閃光弾を打ち上げろ
Far beyond the hill of hope, launching that flashing flare up
千本桜 夜に紛れ 君が歌い僕は踊る
A thousand cherry blossoms lost in night, you sing and I dance
此処は宴 鋼の檻 その断頭台を飛び降りて
This is a banquet in a steel cage, leaping down from the guillotine
千本桜 夜に紛れ 君が歌い僕は踊る
A thousand cherry blossoms lost in night, you sing and I dance
此処は宴 鋼の檻 さあ光線銃を撃ちまくれ
This is a banquet in a steel cage, now fire away with that ray gun!
はーい！
Hi-i!
ということでー、みんなどうでしたか？
And with that, how was everyone?
見て！ キャストオフできるんですよー！
Look! I can cast off my outfit!
はー、ありがとう！
Haah, thank you!
可愛いよ、ありがとう！
"You're cute," thank you!
あのね、ダンスはね、しやすように、リボンをこう袖とかあっさりとかするのね、結構ね、あの、大変だったりとかして
You know, for the dance, making it easier with ribbons on the sleeves was pretty tough.
ちょっとね、ダンスしやすい感じで、それもできるようにしてみました。していただけました。ありがとう！
So I tried to make it easy to dance in, and made it work. Thank you!
あとね、見て！尻尾も取れるんだよ。あ、ケツ尾？
Also, look! My tail can come off too. Ah, "butt tail"?
オケージョ、オケージョですね。
It's an occasion, an occasion tail.
で、見て見て！尻尾は、ぶら、ぶら、ぶら、ぶら！
And look, look! The tail goes swing, swing, swing, swing!
はーい、ということで、もうもっとね、見、見、見、見、見せたいんですけど
Haa-i, so, I want to show you even more, but...
皆さん、あの、次でね、最後の曲になるんですよ。その前に、みんな分かるよね？
Everyone, um, the next song is going to be the last one. But before that, you all know, right?
告知がありますので、いいですか？告知させていただいて。それでは、じゃあ告知、あ、どうぞ、どうぞ！
There's an announcement, is that okay? Allowing me to make an announcement. Well then, an announcement—ah, go ahead, go ahead!
3D新衣装記念2022！
3D New Outfit Commemoration 2022!
本日20時から発売です！
Goes on sale today at 8:00 PM!
やった、かわいい！
Yay, so cute!
というわけで、じゃあ詳しく見ていきますか。
So, let's take a closer look!
こちらがね、あの内容になっております。
Here is the lineup of items.
えっと、セットもあって、単品もあったり。あっ、きたきたきた！
Um, there's a set and individual items. Ah, here it comes!
じゃあ、1つずつ紹介していきましょう。
Let's introduce them one by one.
まずはこちら、新衣装の…あっ！
First is this, the new outfit... Ah!
こちらがね、新衣装のイラストとなっております。
This is the illustration for the new outfit.
黒兎先生が描いてくれました、ありがとうございます！
Drawn by Kuroto-sensei, thank you!
こちらはですね、卓上の…要部になっております。
This is... made into a desktop display.
立てたり、角に金の装飾もあってとても豪華です！
You can stand it up, with gold decoration, very gorgeous!
続いて、湯のみ！
Next, the teacup!
こちらもね、あの新衣装のみこになっております。
This also features Miko in her new outfit.
新衣装のみこが2パターンいて、みこぴーと金時とタイヤキがあります。
There are two patterns of Miko, plus Mikopy, Kintoki, and taiyaki!
リズ先生に描いていただきました。めちゃくちゃかわいい、使ってね！
Illustrated by Rizu-sensei. So cute, please use it!
じゃーん！みんな、覚えている？
Tada! Everyone, do you remember?
みおちゃんとおうまちゃんと一緒にね、行ったね、あの温泉旅行で書いた…
Written during the hot spring trip with Mio-chan and Ouma-chan...
「あきらめない心」を絵皿のにしました！
I made "Arawaka-nai Kokoro" into a decorative plate!
みんな欲しいって言ってたから作ってみたけど、買ってくれるかな？買ってね！
Everyone wanted it, so I made it. Please buy it!
リズ先生のイラストもあり、直筆も描きました。でお皿を飾れるスタンド付きになっております。
Features Rizu-sensei's art and my handwriting, with a display stand.
こちらは、みこのね、新衣装のアクリルスタンドとなっております。
Next, this is Miko's new outfit acrylic stand.
ちょっと大きめで、みこの衣装のモチーフの台座がついてます。やったー！
A bit large, with a base themed on my outfit. Yay!
フルセット購入特典には、みこからのメッセージが書いてある、サイン入りポストカードがついてます！やったー！
The full set bonus includes a postcard with Miko's message and signature!
ここのメッセージはね、何が書いてあるかはお楽しみ。結構書いた、結構落書きした。
What's written in the message is a secret. I doodled a lot.
ということで、お楽しみに！ぜひ買ってね、買ってね！
So look forward to it! Please buy it!
アシタノハナチ
Flowers of tomorrow,
あなたの強さを知る
Knowing your strength,
人の希望 名もなきもの
People's hopes, nameless things,
こころを称えましょう
Let us praise our hearts,
淡く小さき華たちよ
O palely fragrant little flowers,
しなやかに生い茂るのか
Will you grow lush and flexible?
それぞれに言葉にならぬ
Each holding what words cannot express,
懐の奥に 隠した棘の陰
The shadow of thorns hidden deep within,
記憶を抱えて 空に向かっていく
Bearing memories as we head toward the sky.
願いを叫べ 命の限り
Shout out your wish for all your life is worth,
やがて思いは ホシをも貫く
Soon feelings will pierce even the stars.
永い短い時間の果てに あなたの生きた 証はそう
At the end of brief, eternal time, the proof you lived...
土を押し上げて 明日芽を出し
Pushing up the soil, budding tomorrow,
やがて大きな華を咲かせる
And blooming into a great flower.
アシタノハナチ
Flowers of tomorrow,
それは取るに足らない
That is of little account,
まるで風の前の綿毛
Like fluff before the wind.
花びらが宙に浮いた
Petals floated up into the air
舞った一足のサンダル
A single pair of sandals danced
身体ごと宙に浮いて飛んでしまえたら私は
My body floated up into the air as well, if I could fly away...
はららららら
Flutter, flutter...
一人で踊っているだけ
I'm just dancing by myself
ただそれだけだ
That is all there is to it
春先の空気が澄んでいたから
Because the air in early spring was clear,
赤いサンダルを履いて
I put on my red sandals
出かけた先のあの並木のこと
And went out to that row of trees
顔を伏せるように歩く人が多いから
Where so many people walked with their heads down
飛んでいた桜が奇妙に見えたから
And the flying cherry blossoms looked so strangely cheerful,
この道で踊ってやろうと思った
I thought I'd dance on this path.
タッタラタ、ラッタッタ
Tat-tarata, rat-tatta
足を運ぶ
Moving my feet,
タッタラタ、ラッタッタ
Tat-tarata, rat-tatta
音を鳴らす
Making a sound,
タッタラタ、ラッタッタ
Tat-tarata, rat-tatta
春を踊るのさ、桜の下で
Dancing spring away, beneath the cherry blossoms.
花びらが宙に浮いた
Petals floated up into the air
舞った一足のサンダル
A single pair of sandals danced
身体ごと宙に浮いて飛んでしまえたら私は
My body floated up into the air as well, if I could fly away...
はららららら
Flutter, flutter...
一人で踊っているだけ
I'm just dancing by myself
ただそれだけだ
That is all there is to it.
並木道を抜けるほど歩く人の
The cold gazes of the people walking past the row of trees
冷たい視線も気にならなくなってくる
No longer bother me at all.
足がもつれても、髪がほどけても何かが楽しかった
Even if my legs get tangled, even if my hair comes undone, it felt fun.
背中を曲げて生きている私じゃないみたいだ
It's like I'm no longer the me who lives with a hunched back.
花びらの落ち方にだってあなたとの思い出が溢れる
Even in the way the petals fall, memories of you overflow.
うるさいくらいに私を覆うそれをあなたに教えないと
Covering me to the point of being noisy, I have to tell you.
あなたの葬儀を見た
I saw your funeral
なんてことのないアイロニー
Such an unremarkable irony
形だけ何か述べて通り過ぎ行く
People just saying a few words and passing by
あぁ、私は
Ah, I...
はららららら
Flutter, flutter...
一人うな垂れてるだけ、ただそれだけだ
Am just hanging my head alone, that is all there is to it.
花びらが宙に浮いた
Petals floated up into the air
舞った一足のサンダル
A single pair of sandals danced
身体ごと宙に浮いて飛んでしまえたら私は
My body floated up into the air as well...